Aftab Hossain

33- 2911 36st NW Edmonton, Alberta T6L6K4 Phone: (780)-904-6340

Email: munna2089@gmail.com

Profile Summary

Skilled project manager with 10+ years of exemplary service in diverse IT roles. Passionate about utilizing my knowledge and skills to lead technical staff and manage projects. Expert in several project management software and database user interface software programs. Varied experience, including transition programs, administrative roles, and serving as a liaison between technical and business staff. Received multiple accolades, including Employee of the Month. Demonstrated ability to communicate in technical terms with IT professionals and work directly with other staff to explain projects in an understandable manner to ensure projects run smoothly.

Professional Skill

- Project Management
- Business Analyst
- Effective Team Leadership
- Effective Communication Skills
- Mentoring
- Documentation
- Vast Knowledge of Sales Force system
- Customer Relation Management(CRM)
- Web Development
- Database Management
- Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Powerpoint)
- Marketing
- Enterprise resource Planning (ERP) software Specialist.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Phoenix Engravers Bangladesh Ltd, Dhaka, Bangladesh General Manager (IT)

2017 - 2019

Key Responsibilities:

- Developed ERP (Enterprise Resource Planning) Software of the Organization where whole operation executed by the ERP system as like Sales Module, Purchase module, inventory module, account module and customer relation module as well.
- Implemented Roto Gravure Cylinder Manufacturing Data service Development Project.
- Advised upper management on technology, marketing and design and decrease saving cost 0.0% and increase customer up to 500+.
- Performed Tasks central to program progress, including scheduling, budgeting, accounting and resource management.
- Communicated with coached and coordinated project employees of 150+
- Consistently met deadlines with team, achieving commendations for five consecutive months

The Databiz Software Ltd, Dhaka, Bangladesh Project Manager

2014 - 2017

Key Responsibilities:

- Served as the Project Manager for ten active Client programs, totaling \$700,000+ in projected revenue
- Developed and maintained a detailed project plan for each individual account
- Oversaw coordination of the partners and working groups engaged in project work
- Ran ongoing internal program meetings, including weekly status check-ins
- Provided program and project status reports to the project team and company
- Developed a database management program

Key Responsibilities:

- Develop Business architecture using requirement requirements such as scope, process, alternatives and risks.
- Analyze client's business requirements and processes through document analysis, interviews, and workshop and workflow analysis.
- Conduct 5+ level of testing including functional, regression, user acceptance, integration and performance to verify the client's needs are met
- Communicate clients business requirements by constructing easy to understand data and process model

Digital Engravers Ltd, Dhaka, Bangladesh

2004 - 2006

Project Coordinator

Key Responsibilities:

- Managed budget for 3 projects valued at over \$100.000
- Worked on team of two project coordinators in busy construction firm. Handled all. Project facilitation for \$3.5 million in development per year.
- Regularly Educated 150+ employees in the correct interpretation plan

ADDITIONAL EMPLOYMENT

Norseman Inc. Edmonton, AB, Canada

2019 - Present

General Labourer
Key Responsibilities:

- Operate machines and assist other workers with various physical labour tasks
- Effectively communicate with co-workers and supervisors
- Assist plant and/or office staff with moving items which may entail lifting up to 50 lbs.
- Ensure tasks are completed fully and accurately as requested
- Sort, pack, crate and package materials and products
- Maintain safe and clean working environment by complying with procedures, rules, and regulations

EDUCATION

2006-2013

Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.) in Computer Science and Engineering State University of Bangladesh, Dhaka, Bangladesh

TRAINING

2011-2012

- OOP(Object Oriented Program) IN PHP from IBCX PRIMAX , Dhaka Bangladesh
- OOP(Object Oriented Program) IN DOT NET from BASIS, Dhaka, Bangladesh

LANGUAGE/TECHNICAL SKILL

- Basic OOP(Object Oriented Programming)
- MVC4 Framework
- C, C++, C#, Java,
- MYSQL, SQL Database
- Basic hardware troubleshooting
- Windows 10 operating system
- Internet browsing, emailing

- ASP DOT NET
- Entity Framework
- Java Script, AJAX, JQuery, Joomla, Wordpress
- Codeigniter Framework for PHP
- Microsoft Office & office 365